Leonard Bocour Papers
Leonard Bocour Papers
1953-1964
Bocour, Leonard, 1910-1993.
0.5 linear ft.
Biographical material, incoming and outgoing correspondence, and paint orders. Incoming letters of Walter Burt Adams, David Aronson, Aaron Bohrod, Warren Brandt, Alexander Brook, Lawrence Calcagno, Bernard Chaet, David C. Driskell, Herman Maril, Gregorio Prestopino, Walter Quirt, and others.
148854
Biographical History
American art collector, businessman, founder of Bocour Artist Colors Incorporated.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1953 to 1964, the Leonard Bocour Papers consists of biographical material and correspondence of the paint manufacturer, lecturer, art collector, artist, and founder of Bocour Artist Colors Incorporated (b. 1910). Comprised of incoming letters, outgoing typescript carbons, and paint orders, the Correspondence-Subject Files documents Bocour's personal and professional relationships with various art organizations and artists (Walter Burt Adams, David Aronson, George Biddle, Aaron Bohrod, Warren Brandt, Alexander Brook, Lawrence Calcagno, Bernard Chaet, David C. Driskell, Jo Hopper, Walter Kamys, Rockwell Kent, Herman Maril, Edward Millman, Gregorio Prestopino, Walter Quirt, and others).
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged alphabetically by correpondent's last name.
Related Material
See also the
Aaron Bohrod Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Adams, Walter Burt.; Aronson, David, 1923-2015.; Bocour, Leonard, 1910-1993.; Bohrod, Aaron.; Brandt, Warren, 1918-2002.; Brook, Alexander, 1898-1980.; Calcagno, Lawrence, 1913-1993.; Chaet, Bernard.; Driskell, David C.; Maril, Herman.; Prestopino, Gregorio.; Quirt, Walter, 1902-1968.; Bocour Artist Colors Incorporated.; Art -- Collectors and collecting.; Artists.; Paint.; Paint industry and trade -- United States.; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical Material
  - Biographical material on Leonard Bocour (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - A, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Adams, Walter Burt, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Aronson, David, 1958; 1963 (Box 1)
  - B, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Beerbohm, Marvin, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Biddle, George, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Bohrod, Aaron, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Brandt, Warren, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Brook, Alexander, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Busa, Peter, 1963 (Box 1)
  - C-F, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Calcagno, Lawrence, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Chaet, Bernard R., 1957-1958; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Covington, Harrison W., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Daly, Norman, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Danes, Gibson A., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Dodd, Lamar, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Driskell, David C., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Feldman, Walter, 1963 (Box 1)
  - G-K, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Green, Myra, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Holbrook, Hollis H., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Hopper, Jo, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Kamys, Walter, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Kaufman, Irving, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Kent, Rockwell, undated (Box 1)
  - L-M, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Lahee, Arnold Warburton, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Laird, Don, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Leighton, Thomas C., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Loew, Michael, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Lord, Jack, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Maril, Herman, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Massin, Eugene, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mesches, Arnold, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Millman, Edward, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mulcahy, Freda, 1958 (Box 1)
  - N-P, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Noland, Kenneth Clifton, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Prestopino, Gregorio, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Price, Helen F., 1953; 1958 (Box 1)
  - Q-Z, unidentified, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Quirt, Walter, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Quisgard, Liz Whitney, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Williams, Esther, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Dora, 1958 (Box 1)